Guide to the Beatrice S. Cosmey Papers, 1928-1930
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Beatrice S. Cosmey Papers
1928-1930
Cosmey, Beatrice S.
0.6 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The collection consists of Beatrice Cosmey's memoirs of her travels and teaching experience in India through correspondence from Beatrice Cosmey to her family and friends, as well as a scrapbook.
Biographical Note
Beatrice S. Cosmey graduated from Vassar in 1925 and earned her master's degree at Columbia in 1928. Following three years of teaching math at the Packer Collegiate Institute in Brooklyn between 1925 and 1928, she served as head of the math department at the Woman's Christian College in Madras, India (1928 - 1930), the sister college of Mount Holyoke in India, and the director of mathematics at the St. Agatha School in New York City (1930 - 1936). In 1936 she began teaching at the Shipley School of Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania and in 1941 became responsible for student War activities. In addition, she studied and participated in research at the University of Pennsylvania and the University of Chicago. While in Chicago Miss Cosmey spent two years restructuring the mathematics curriculum at the Dalton School. Returning to New York in 1947, she joined Elizabeth Parmelee as head mistress of the Calhoun School, a position from which she retired in 1969. During her life Miss Cosmey also served as treasurer of the Headmistresses Association of the East and Secretary of the Assoc. Board of Women's Christian College, Madras, India.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of Beatrice Cosmey's memoirs of her travels and teaching experience in India through correspondence from Beatrice Cosmey to her family and friends, as well as a scrapbook.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Women's Christian College (Madras, India)
Subjects:
Education--India; Universities and colleges--India; Women--Education--India--Madras
Places:
India--Description and travel--1901-1946
Document Types:
Scrapbooks
VCL Categories:
East Asia, South Asia, and India; Education; Family; Travel
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2009.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary A. Thompson.
Container List
- Letters from Beatrice Cosmey to family
  - 6 letters, 1928 Jun 24 - Jul 11 (Folder 1.1)
  - 3 letters, 1928 Jul 14-22 (Folder 1.2)
  - 3 letters, 1928 Jul 26 - Aug 5 (Folder 1.3)
  - 4 letters, 1928 Aug 7-27 (Folder 1.4)
  - 5 letters, 1928 Aug 28 - Sep 19 (Folder 1.5)
  - 3 letters, 1928 Sep 23-27 (Folder 1.6)
  - 3 letters, 1928 Oct 3-20 (Folder 1.7)
  - 5 letters, 1928 Oct 21 - Nov 18 (Folder 1.8)
  - 5 letters, 1928 Nov-Dec (Folder 1.9)
  - 3 letters, 1929 Jan 4-16 (Folder 1.10)
  - 4 letters, 1929 Jan 24 - Feb 21 (Folder 1.11)
  - 2 letters, 1929 Mar 7-14 (Folder 1.12)
  - 3 letters, 1 fragment, 1929 Mar 14 - Apr 4 (Folder 1.13)
  - 4 letters, 1929 Apr 22 - May 12 (Folder 2.1)
  - 3 letters, 1929 May 19 - Jun 6 (Folder 2.2)
  - 5 letters, 1929 Jun 27 - Aug 1 (Folder 2.3)
  - 5 letters, 1929 Aug 11 - Sep 10 (Folder 2.4)
  - 4 letters, 1929 Sep 15 - Oct 3 (Folder 2.5)
  - 7 letters, 1929 Oct 23 - Dec 19 (Folder 2.6)
  - 4 letters, 1929 Dec 31 - 1930 Feb 2 (Folder 2.7)
  - 2 letters, 1930 Feb 19-24 (Folder 2.8)
  - 3 letters, 1930 Mar 13-23 (Folder 2.9)
  - 1 letter, 1 fragment, 1930 Apr 15-21 (Folder 2.10)
  - 2 letters, 1930 Apr 25 - May 9 (Folder 2.11)
  - 3 letters, 1930 May 23 - Jun 9 (Folder 2.12)
- Letters from Beatrice Cosmey to friends
  - 3 joint letters to: Miss A.W. Sleight, Miss Edith Seaborg, Miss Beatrice Bagg, Miss Mabel Lewish, Mrs. Edward Eawes, Mrs. Abner Newton, Miss Madeleine Bubier, Miss Eloise T. Anderson, Mrs. J.A. Anderson, Miss Ruth Newcomb, Mrs. Robert K. Burns, Miss Katherine Ogden, Miss Gladys M. Green, Mrs. Lloyd E. Dale, Mrs. W.D. Middleton, Miss Erdice G. Bauwgadener, Mrs. H.W. Bauer, Misses Dorothy and Miriam Rich, Mrs. J.S. Arnold, Mrs. I.T. Cosmey, 1929 Jan 24 - 1930 Apr 25 (Folder 2.13)
- Miscellaneous
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box 3)